[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d9", "question": "What movie starred Sean Penn playing the role of gay rights activist Harvey Milk?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaa", "question": "What citrus \u00adflavored soft drink was introduced by Coca-Cola in 1979 to compete with Pepsi's Mountain Dew?", "answer": "Mello Yello", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0f", "question": "Who won her first Best Actress Oscar for the movie \"Sophie's Choice\"?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08a", "question": "Who kept searching for his long lost salt shaker?", "answer": "Jimmy Buffett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b528", "question": "What does the beer widget do?", "answer": "Manages the beer's head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ad", "question": "What are the six most abundant Greenhouse Gases?", "answer": "Water vapour, carbond dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, ozone and chlorofluorocarbons.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339792", "question": "Which TV show had Russian spies Boris Badenov and Natasha Fatale?", "answer": "The Bullwinkle Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe657a4ae7e414034b5aedf", "question": "In the \"Book of Judges\", Othniel defeats Cushan-Rishathaim, the king of what land?", "answer": "Aram", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6719552a821ff76ae8b24", "question": "What manufacturer introduced \"Pringles\" potato chips in 1967?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a634", "question": "What city is home to the University of Oregon?", "answer": "Eugene", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a3", "question": "What country's name is the local pronunciation of the name of its British discoverer, Thomas Gilbert?", "answer": "Kiribati", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c08d", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f369fa5fdd6dd25324da", "question": "Which film producer said \"Anyone who goes to a psychiatrist ought to have his head examined\"?", "answer": "Samuel Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5967613d2b59efe0e9417ea2", "question": "The song \"Good Girl\" was the 12th Top 20 hit for what artist?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007849bbd51d85e222ab65c", "question": "What was the first fruit that was eaten on the moon?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889a", "question": "Where did Gulliver find a race of tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b729", "question": "What were Frosty's last words in the carol?", "answer": "I'll be back again some day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a5535d3e1c6f9840ba31a3", "question": "Who won the 1990 Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a7", "question": "Who sang the Song \"Gangsta's Paradise\"?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f82dfe83fe1f2a824c29", "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "She was born on April 21, 1926 at 2:40 A.M.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b588", "question": "When was Twitter first launched?", "answer": "2006", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c309", "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?", "answer": "206", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e4", "question": "Born in 1846, who was William Frederick Cody better known as?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a62a32ebb971c1417fb91", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2f", "question": "What NFL team moved into Soldier Field in 1971?", "answer": "Chicago Bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a2", "question": "What was Michael Flaherty's job on the TV show \"Spin City\"?", "answer": "Deputy mayor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339719", "question": "At what age did Ray Charles become totally blind?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339691", "question": "What movie contains the line \"I'm going to make him an offer he can't refuse\"?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a8", "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's famous horse?", "answer": "Bucephalas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc1c76ce05a3942286f15", "question": "What was Luke Skywalker's original name?", "answer": "Like Starkiller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b516", "question": "What renowned sour mash whisky is made in Lynchburg, Tennessee?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce1", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by Jay-Z and Damon Dash?", "answer": "Rocawear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abcbd6490a8cc1a6e529b", "question": "In \"Ready Player One\" by Ernest Cline, who must the player defeat in order to obtain the copper key?", "answer": "Acererak", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6017372e44491cbd7c5a1785", "question": "During the American Civil War, what ship engaged the iron-clad ship USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the USS Monitor engaged the CSS Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905a", "question": "Painter Salvador Dali was a native of which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38a", "question": "What was the capital of East Germany?", "answer": "East Berlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b341", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba58", "question": "What comedian provided the voice for the AFLAC duck in TV commercials until he was let go?", "answer": "Gilbert Gottfried", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fae", "question": "What nickname is shared by Charles Russell, Harold Reese, and Paul Reubens?", "answer": "Pee-Wee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06f", "question": "What does Shin Hayata use to turn into Ultraman?", "answer": "Beta Capsule", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b6", "question": "In what city would you find Balboa Park?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2d", "question": "What date is inscribed in the tablet held by the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "July 4, 1776", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173c8644491cbd7c5a17a6", "question": "How did Friday get its name?", "answer": "Coming from the Nordic goddess Freyja and the Germanic goddess Frigg, it was called\u00a0Fr\u012b\u0121ed\u00e6\u0121\u00a0in Old English.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ae", "question": "What is added to copper to make bronze?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03a", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who did Mayor West send back to the fifth dimension?", "answer": "Alex Trebek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f1", "question": "Shortbread originated in what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907b", "question": "What is the meaning of the Latin phrase \"cum grano salis\"?", "answer": "With a grain of salt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c250", "question": "What do you call an animal that eats both plants and animals?", "answer": "An Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cacf877e98cb97778a0c", "question": "Which Arab country houses the Rub Al-Khali or Empty Quarter, the largest continuous sand desert in the world?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b640", "question": "What comes out of a hawsehole?", "answer": "Ship's cable", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe530581bf59ab7d2e38119", "question": "Which American family dynasty is Anderson Cooper related to?", "answer": "Vanderbilt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078bab0eee65b76b9f266b", "question": "For what is Matthew Webb famous?", "answer": "He was the first man to swim the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad90", "question": "What historic event occurred on December 24, 1968?", "answer": "The crew of Apollo 8 read scripture to the world", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339658", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", why did Bart and Homer have to work at the carnival?", "answer": "Bart wrecked Hitler's car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c80", "question": "Who was the first musical host of \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90d", "question": "Who lost part of his ear to the teeth of Mike Tyson in 1997?", "answer": "Evander Holyfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f742fa9e54d890926f6f4", "question": "What country has competitive office chair racing?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b920", "question": "What do Noodlers catch with their bare hands?", "answer": "Catfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590721963745b36be73039f8", "question": "What were Frosty the Snowman\u2019s eyes made out of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590683dfff9c0647b50a80ab", "question": "Which album won the 2016 Grammy Award for \"Album of the Year\"?", "answer": "1989", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c505", "question": "What is a group of apes called?", "answer": "A shrewdness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17c", "question": "Which member of Guns 'n' Roses was born in Hampstead, England?", "answer": "Slash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963f", "question": "In which country was Greta Garbo born?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"kumquat\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8e", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Cathy Moriarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e9a736d4be723796b51", "question": "What is Toronto\u2019s Pearson International Airport code?", "answer": "YYZ", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0af7ae662d71a53650fbe", "question": "Who was the first rapper to win the Pulitzer Prize in the music category?", "answer": "Kendrick Lamar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd8", "question": "Who originally sang the 1973 song that became a big Dixie Chicks hit in 2002?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d86", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Manhunter\" based on?", "answer": "Red Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81d", "question": "Starfish belong to what animal phylum, whose name means \"spiny skin\"?", "answer": "Echinoderms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0df", "question": "In what year was the \"Star Spangled Banner\" designated the US National Anthem?", "answer": "1931", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5b8d6ce05a3942286e17", "question": "Frank Sinatra rewrote \"High Hopes\" for what president's campaign?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc1", "question": "What is a gricer interested in?", "answer": "Trains", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd09", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by Tony the Tiger?", "answer": "Kellogg's Sugar Frosted Flakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071da73745b36be73039db", "question": "Who became the first American in space in 1961?", "answer": "Alan Shepard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd32", "question": "What soccer team won the Premier League in 2004?", "answer": "Arsenal FC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910d", "question": "What is the name of Viktor Frankl's best-selling 1946 book?", "answer": "Man's Search for Meaning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e5", "question": "What sport has its name abbreviated to BMX?", "answer": "Bicycle Moto-cross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d49", "question": "What year did The Louvre open as a museum?", "answer": "1793", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00b", "question": "What Merrilee Rush hit was written by Chip Taylor, the brother of actor Jon Voight?", "answer": "Angel of the Morning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f7a8fe83fe1f2a824c24", "question": "Who was the first woman to contest for the office of the President of the United States of America?", "answer": "In 1872, Victoria Woodhull became the first woman to run for the position of President of the United States.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da1", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Absolute Power\"?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40d", "question": "Devil's Island, once the world's most notorious penal colony, is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adfc", "question": "What was the last city the British held onto, two years after the last battle of the American Revolution?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c5", "question": "Who released the album \"The Cry of Love\" in 1971?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ec", "question": "The Kung San people live in what area of Africa?", "answer": "Kalahari Desert in Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b372061c3f17ccc40c8e21", "question": "The detective novel \"The Body in the library\" was written by which novelist?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5fd6632fa5bfecdd737e084d", "question": "Who had the highest grossing tour of 2018?", "answer": "Ed Sheeran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b710eee65b76b9f2668", "question": "What name was given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d10", "question": "What nationality was author Jules Verne?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2c", "question": "What began on the early morning of Sunday, September 2, 1666, near London Bridge?", "answer": "The Great Fire of London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f72bba9e54d890926f6ed", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e6", "question": "What are the two main ingredients of mayonnaise?", "answer": "Oil and egg yolk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee7", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister on V-J day?", "answer": "Clement Attlee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5151fff04d658268c92e7", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96d", "question": "In what country is Africa's northernmost point?", "answer": "Tunisia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c937", "question": "Which is a small flightless bird, also New Zealand's national symbol?", "answer": "Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a303", "question": "Who was Randy Mario Poffo better known as?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ffa401dd7bf43be5e863", "question": "Who said, \"It does not matter how slowly you go as long as you do not stop.\"?", "answer": "Confucius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133979b", "question": "Saddle shoes, poodle skirts and motorcycle jackets were popular in what decade?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25b", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with abolishing slavery?", "answer": "Thirteenth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad10", "question": "What city was talk show host Jerry Springer mayor of from 1977-1978?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70c", "question": "Chicago is located on the shore of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f4511af848b908361b872", "question": "What colors are featured on the Chinese flag?", "answer": "Red and yellow.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b1744b5bb2d29f81593b6fc", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Aliens\", what was Newt's real name?", "answer": "Rebecca Jorden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9043401dd7bf43be5e873", "question": "What was the theme of the first Macy's Thanksgiving Parade?", "answer": "Mother Goose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902b", "question": "Who created the fictional detective Nero Wolfe?", "answer": "Rex Stout", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e5f0bafd274615ecf514530", "question": "What brand of melty cheese was first introduced to the mass market in 1928?", "answer": "Velveeta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b00855722f97b22684da", "question": "In the \"Harry Potter\" universe, who dies during the third Tri-wizard Tournament?", "answer": "Cedric Diggory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c683", "question": "Which metal, in its purest form, has the highest melting point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf78d0b37b32637bdc44bb", "question": "What is the name of Marvin and Trina's son in the musical \"Falsettos\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c437", "question": "What is the top layer of Earth called?", "answer": "Crust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a827", "question": "What international city is served by Charles de Gaulle Airport?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029d91cad1ec93f27df74f", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24f", "question": "Who replaced Ronnie James Dio in Black Sabbath?", "answer": "Ian Gillan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a409", "question": "Through which continent does the Crocodile River run?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98b", "question": "What is energy typically measured in what SI units?", "answer": "Joules", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7fc5ff048f679a45ac15", "question": "What is the lightest element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a262", "question": "What is the name of the summer camp in the \"Friday the 13th\" movie series?", "answer": "Camp Crystal Lake\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1cddf7bd84c0ea43ad430", "question": "In Norse mythology Odin traded an eye for what?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72cbb2d0874f1a5e2d1c22", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b8f6364247bf200fb885", "question": "What is the capital of the Australia's Northern Territory?", "answer": "Darwin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338acb", "question": "What author's novel \"East of Eden\" was a symbolic recreation of the story of Cain and Abel?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b355", "question": "From whom did the US buy the Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e97db24f84e0b9f9ffce", "question": "What precious metal did alchemists call \"luna\"?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eb13fe83fe1f2a824bf7", "question": "Who did the German Nazi regime replace Santa Claus with?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f2", "question": "Who directed and starred in the 1973 movie \"High Plains Drifter\"?", "answer": "Clint Eastwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a5", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f1", "question": "What was Babe Ruth's real name?", "answer": "George Herman Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a884", "question": "At what national capital does the White Nile join the Blue Nile?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6eeaa9e54d890926f6cc", "question": "In which country can you find the world's tallest twin building?", "answer": "Malaysia -- The Petronas Twin Towers in Kuala Lumpur are 1,483 feet tall and have a 400 ft. solid foundation, the world's largest.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a448", "question": "Which country is home to the spring festival called \"Holi\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31c", "question": "Which character did John Ritter play on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "Jack Tripper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a064", "question": "Who directed the monochrome sequences at the beginning and end of the 1939 movie \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "King Vidor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f01", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6cd", "question": "Which US state's highest mountain is Mt. Elbert?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a298", "question": "In musical terms, what does \"Da capo\" mean?", "answer": "From the beginning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a3", "question": "What year were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1924", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ef", "question": "How many squares are there on a standard Scrabble board?", "answer": "225", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1b9ff6756c9b30ba14fb", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d77", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Children's Crusade\"?", "answer": "Slaughterhouse-Five", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2e", "question": "What four evangelists wrote the Gospels?", "answer": "Matthew, Mark, Luke, John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11f", "question": "Somniphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c13", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the seventh plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Storms of fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da6", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Snout?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc58", "question": "The dish, \"Pad Thai\" originates from what Asian country?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b03de662d71a53650fc4", "question": "What feature marks the entrance to the Louvre?", "answer": "Glass pyramid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa40e0c73aa70ea0b70b0b", "question": "Which U.S. state claims to be the diner capital of the world?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ea", "question": "What term for an adult male gorilla comes from a distinctive patch of hair?", "answer": "Silverback", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c54", "question": "Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album was released in what year?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e6", "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?", "answer": "Spokane, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3a", "question": "By what name is the author Theodor Geisel better known?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54e", "question": "What digit does not exist in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b3724d1c3f17ccc40c8e23", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aba", "question": "What children's literature character is usually accompanied by his canine pal Ribsy?", "answer": "Henry Huggins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e5", "question": "What popular Motown group was originally known as \"The Primettes\"?", "answer": "The Supremes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca17", "question": "What is used to measure horizontal and vertical angles in surveying?", "answer": "A theodolite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b47d01dd7bf43be5e7c1", "question": "All astronauts who visit the International Space Station must learn what language?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a01", "question": "What is the name of Austin Powers' boss?", "answer": "Basil Exposition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb8b07e83c707845b2135", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0db23fcbed638185eaa07", "question": "Which U.S. city has the most coffee shops per capita?", "answer": "Juneau, Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c219", "question": "What year were the first Olympic Games after World War II held?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea43d8ff048f679a45ab89", "question": "What is the scientific study of human movement?", "answer": "Kinesiology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd667cea5bfecdd737e086c", "question": "How many elevators are there in the Empire State Building?", "answer": "73", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d993e08b8581f80b092b4", "question": "What critically, and commercially successful indie game released in 2017, borrowed its art style from 1930s cartoons?", "answer": "Cuphead", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cba", "question": "What is the third letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Gamma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e0", "question": "What magazine introduced a paper doll named Betsy in 1951?", "answer": "McCall's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0e5ff048f679a45aaaa", "question": "Venustraphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Beautiful women", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571c8667df192a942e3375", "question": "Who is Edson Arantes do Nascimento more widely known as?", "answer": "Pele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Electric Kool-Aid Acid Test\"?", "answer": "Tom Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961f", "question": "What actor played Bill the Butcher in the 2002 movie \"Gangs of New York\"?", "answer": "Daniel Day Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a663", "question": "Which state is home to the Pribilof Islands?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ffbaa3a3a814d89068c68", "question": "What is Freddie Mercury's birth name?", "answer": "Farrokh Bulsara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde5129c6c6b019850c9a8d", "question": "Who was the first King of the Northern Ten Tribes of Israel during the time of the Divided Kingdom?", "answer": "Jeroboam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbf0b6ce05a3942286efa", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Material Girl\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66044a5bfecdd737e0832", "question": "What was the first pizza chain in the United States?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b3fce662d71a53650fe7", "question": "Which European town inspired Vincent van Gogh's famous \u201cStarry Night\u201d?", "answer": "Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b121", "question": "In what decade did Dr. Christiaan Barnard perform the first successful human heart transplant?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ad", "question": "When did J. D. Salinger publish the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1a", "question": "A person who has been canonized has been granted what status?", "answer": "Sainthood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe52db81bf59ab7d2e3810d", "question": "What is the best-selling ice-cream flavor in the US?", "answer": "Vanilla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a62e32ebb971c1417fb94", "question": "The \"Turbot War\" was a fishing dispute between Canada and what other country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ac9701dd7bf43be5e76e", "question": "Which religion places importance on proper care for bonsai trees?", "answer": "Zen Buddhism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24c", "question": "What year was Bryan Adams' \"Cuts Like a Knife\" album released in?", "answer": "1983", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce6", "question": "What is Mr. Freeze's given name?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f97", "question": "What TV title role did Jay North play for four seasons?", "answer": "Dennis the Menace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21f", "question": "When was \"Macho Man\" Randy Savage born?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb58155dad637d903c880e", "question": "Venice's famed Bridge of Sighs connects two what?", "answer": "Prisons -- The bridge connects an old prison inside the Doge's Palace to a newer one across the Rio di Palazzo.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cdd6bb53d1af658864ed", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe5224b1bf59ab7d2e380e6", "question": "When was \"Silent Night\" written?", "answer": "1818", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3fb", "question": "Which US state is home to the Finger Lakes?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339430", "question": "What comedic duo of the 1920s and 1930s were real-life best friends?", "answer": "Laurel & Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad40", "question": "What was the name of the plane that dropped the atomic bomb on Nagasaki?", "answer": "Bockscar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cc9ed0874f1a5e2d1c24", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51a8aff04d658268c9306", "question": "Odysseus left home to fight in what war?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067ed5ff9c0647b50a807f", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0a", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Edge of Reason\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's Diary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c555", "question": "What subatomic particle has no charge?", "answer": "Neutron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e1", "question": "What do SETI programs search for?", "answer": "Extraterrestrial Intelligence", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad57", "question": "Queen Mary of England made her reputation by trying to rid her country of what segment of the population?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c45f877e98cb9777899e", "question": "Which country was known as South West Africa until 1990?", "answer": "Namibia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c377", "question": "What did Clive Sinclair call the world's first pocket calculator, launched in 1972?", "answer": "Sinclair Executive", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b0", "question": "What did the Lady of the Lake give King Arthur?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4e", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Dumb and Dumber\"?", "answer": "Cam Neely", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19c", "question": "What nationality is tennis player Martina Hingis?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a072", "question": "What planet did Alf come from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a963", "question": "What split up into Gondwanaland and Laurasia?", "answer": "Pangaea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c72bfbde8045e48466bf", "question": "What does a cyanometer measure?", "answer": "Blueness of the sky -- It was developed by 18th-century Swiss scientist, Horace-B\u00e9n\u00e9dict de Saussure.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948d", "question": "What did Seymour give to Jake as a birthday present in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "A camera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c123", "question": "What is the Binot-Simon Scale used to measure?", "answer": "Intelligence", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35b", "question": "How many feet do snails have?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ff", "question": "What Poker hand comprises three of a kind and a pair?", "answer": "A full house", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c9", "question": "What queen were the Virgin Islands named for in 1627?", "answer": "Elizabeth I", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2a", "question": "Who wrote \"The Pisan Cantos\" while in prison?", "answer": "Ezra Pound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab92a0b8cce1e6fda7053", "question": "The most popular car color in the USA for 2019 was which color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f7eeb4e2c7fbd389674d", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a9da01dd7bf43be5e753", "question": "Why did Jack and Jill go up the hill?", "answer": "Fetch a pail of water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dffa09616e6c6d4eba4fe", "question": "Which US Holiday is celebrated on October 12th?", "answer": "Columbus Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049d61cf93664eb10486ad", "question": "Julia Louis-Dreyfus was born on Friday, January 13, of what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba20", "question": "Which sport would you be playing when competing for the Davis Cup?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3231a6bf195a31e15d7386", "question": "Who shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize with Menachem Begin?", "answer": "Mohamed Anwar Al-Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339262", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's dog in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60d", "question": "Who created the original Barbie doll?", "answer": "Ruth Handler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338937", "question": "What does the fairy godmother transform into a coach for Cinderella?", "answer": "A pumpkin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9031501dd7bf43be5e86d", "question": "What was the original name for Gummy Bears?", "answer": "Dancing Bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaee37e83c707845b20f8", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071c853745b36be73039cc", "question": "What is the name of the first space launch facility?", "answer": "Baikonur Cosmodrome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e9106b8d7247dfc0fa00316", "question": "Where did the movie \"Stuart Little\" take place in?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c258", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation CPU stand for?", "answer": "Central Processing Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf7965b37b32637bdc44be", "question": "What shape is a wombat\u2019s fecal matter?", "answer": "Cubic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b2fffb6c85e9e634ff41", "question": "Despite being released at the end of 1998, who had a  #1 hit in 1999 with the song \"Fly Away\"?", "answer": "Lenny Kravitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4a46ff048f679a45abc2", "question": "What inventor first used the term \"Horse Power\"?", "answer": "James Watt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904980dcf93664eb1048685", "question": "What is activated for freckles to appear?", "answer": "Melanocytes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c50", "question": "Who directed the 1968 \"Planet of the Apes\" movie?", "answer": "Franklin J. Schaffner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162c2ef01ec323f849172e", "question": "Who was the legendary front man for the band Roxy Music?", "answer": "Bryan Ferry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f9", "question": "In which 1998 movie did the main character said \"You got the wrong guy. I'm the Dude, man.\"?", "answer": "The Big Lebowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65c171f3c0ead6880d60d", "question": "What did the Russian people do with Vladimir Lenin's body after his death in 1924?", "answer": "Displayed it publicly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a865", "question": "What is the capital of Montenegro?", "answer": "Podgorica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65a", "question": "Hall of Fame running back Jim Brown played his entire pro career for which NFL team?", "answer": "Cleveland Browns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7759ceec85e375820b30e", "question": "Where are Zinfandel grapes from?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1e", "question": "What key is to the right of T on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a53", "question": "What is the subtitle of the classic novel \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Life Among the Lowly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab37", "question": "Avarua is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4eea106d333868d34d775", "question": "What would you have if you recombined Laurasia and Gondwanaland?", "answer": "Pangea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a212", "question": "What was the name of the dog in the TV series \"Fraggle Rock\"?", "answer": "Sprocket", "category": "entertainment"}]